Samantha Maas

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(937)638-7061 samanthajmaas@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/samanthajmaas https://github.com/samanthajmaas https://samanthajmaas.github.io/

ABOUT

Prior to starting my journey in software development, I was working in the education field as an elementary teacher. I am grateful for the experiences that being a teacher gave me, including the ability to mentor students, being able to solve problems on the spot, and collaborating with a team to achieve goals. After relocating to Nashville and being introduced to the technology community, I felt that it was the perfect career path for me to continue using these skills while also using the new passion that I found I have for coding. I'm excited to continue this path while learning new things every day!

PROJECTS

My Closet Keeper | Individual Project

https://github.com/samanthajmaas/MyClosetKee per-FrontEndCapstone

My Closet Keeper is a single page responsive CRUD application that allows users to keep their personal closet up to date by allowing them to create outfits and plan their suitcase for upcoming trips. This application was built using React framework for JavaScript and was styled using CSS, React-Strap and the Material UI. This application also explored the use of Cloudinary to allow the user to upload their own images.

Rare | Group Project

 $\label{lem:https://github.com/samanthajmaas/rare-media-moguls} https://github.com/samanthajmaas/rare-media-moguls$

Rare is a responsive application created in a collaborative group using **React.js** framework, **CSS**, and **HTML** for front-end development and **Python/Django** and **SQLite** for backend. This application provides an easy environment for users to be able to share articles, comment and react to content, and subscribe to other users. Personally responsible for building the *update* functionality on the backend and frontend for user's posts, restricting user's capabilities depending on their status, and styling different components for a more user-friendly experience.

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Web Development \parallel Certificate

BALL STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science \parallel Elementary Education

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Nashville, TN

Full Stack Software Developer

July 2020-Present

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects. Tech Stack: Python/Django; React.js; JavaScript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL fundamentals.

- \bullet Created one-page applications featuring full CRUD functionality using React.js, JavaScript and HTML
- Planned for and designed applications using CSS and React-Strap
- Simulated a professional work environment by utilizing SCRUM framework and Git/GitHub features during group project sprints
- Used Python, SQLite and Django Rest framework to create and query JSON Server databases
- Grew comfortable with remote style work through the daily use of Zoom and Slack for communication

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RUTHERFORD COUNTY SCHOOLS

Smyrna, TN

5th Grade Reading and Social Studies Teacher

August 2019-August 2020

- Pulled appropriate resources for Language Arts that aligned with Tennessee State Education Standards and Rutherford counties curriculum guide
- Created engaging, hands-on, and appropriate lessons
- Solved problems on a daily basis by being flexible while still sticking to the original plans
- Regularly analyzed data to better meet students' individual learning needs and implemented necessary changes to curriculum
- Engaged in regular team meetings to plan and solve problems in students' behavior, curriculum implementation, and/or issues in school wide polices
- Utilized technology used school wide including Skyward and Microsoft Suite
- Explored other uses for technology in the classroom by using resources like I-Ready and Clever

FAIRLAWN LOCAL SCHOOLS

Sidney, OH

4th-6th Grade Reading and Social Studies Teacher

April 2017-August 2019

- Created and mapped out curriculum for Language Arts and Social Studies that aligned with Ohio State Education Standards
- Created guided reading curriculum that was implemented in all grades K-5
- Learned how to solve minor problems by being flexible, including student behavior issues or curriculum implementation
- Regularly met with team to plan curriculum and reflect on classroom management implementation
- Engaged in regular collaborative meetings with parents
- Utilized technology used school with including Progress Book and school email
- Explored other uses for technology by using resources like Newsela, Common Lit, and No Red Ink

MINSTER BANK

Minster, OH

Bank Teller

July 2016-September 2017

- Managed customers' bank accounts by performing regular deposits, withdraws, and other bank procedures
- Organized customer information and branch paperwork
- Utilized bank technology including teller program, and online training platform
- Worked with branch leadership and co-workers to create a friendly and effective banking experience for customers